National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5584
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service State Files. (Box 15)
  - California - General Correspondence -, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Correspondence re WPA funding for study of Black unemployment in California. Alleged discrimination against Blacks by the California State Employment Service.
  - California - Survey -, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Report of 1935 study on white collar and skilled and professional Blacks in Los Angeles, County, California funded by the WPA. Includes racial statistics on population, educational level, extent of training and the extent to which the training affected their socio-economic status. Also report including racial statistics on population (1910-1935), emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry and California State Employment Service data divided by race in Los Angeles, Oakland, and San Francisco, California.
  - Colorado - Complaints -, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Alleged discrimination against a Black man by Colorado State Employment Service in civil service merit examinations and staffing.
  - Colorado - Survey -, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients and unemployment in Colorado and Denver.
  - Connecticut - General Correspondence -, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    List of members and conference report of the State Advisory Council of the Connecticut State Employment Service.
  - Connecticut - Survey -, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Statistics on population, 1910-1933, emergency relief recipients and occupations of Blacks in Hartford, New Haven and Connecticut.
  - Delaware - General Correspondence -, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing by the Delaware State Employment Service
  - Delaware - Survey -, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Statistics on population, 1910-1935, emergency relief recipients, unemployment and occupations divided by race in Wilmington and Delaware.
  - Florida - Complaints -, 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks in civil service competitive examinations and employee placement opportunities by the Florida State Employment Service. Correspondence alleging discrimination by unions and employers against Black mechanic, farm hand, and shipping industry employees.
  - Florida - General Correspondence -, 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment with the Florida State Employment Service. Discrimination against Blacks at the service, where racial segregation exists. Reports on the improvement of treatment of Blacks in civil service merit examinations and employee placements.
  - Florida - Survey, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Statistics on occupational groups of job applicants to Florida State Employment Service, divided by race.
  - Georgia - Complaints -, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks by Atlanta, Georgia State Employment Service in civil service merit examinations. Alleged discrimination against Blacks in Georgia resulting in unemployment and poverty.
  - Georgia - General Correspondence -, 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    Alleged discrimination regarding the dismissal of Black employees from the Atlanta, Georgia State Employment Service. Black job applicants request aid in securing employment with the United States Employment Service.
  - Georgia - Survey -, 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Report on the relationship between the Georgia State Employment service and Black job applicants. Racial statistics on population, 1910-1933, emergency relief recipients, occupations and local industry in Atlanta and Georgia. Correspondence arranging conferences on Black labor in Georgia.
- U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service State Files. (Box 16)
  - Illinois - Metropolitan Chicago Conference on Employment Problems of the Negro - 1940 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Speeches to the Conference concerning Black employment in white collar, professional, utilities and government sectors; the place of Blacks in the Social Security Program; Industrial aspect and economic aspect; the Chicago Black occupational picture; Black Labor Symposium includes discussion of training needs and employment opportunities in meat packing, iron and steel, manufacturing, hotel and restaurant and construction industries. Training and opportunities sought for day workers and personal and custodial service. Black youth in the employment picture and the Black woman workers are subjects of discussion.
  - Illinois - Chicago Conference on Occupational Status and Employment Opportunities for Black Workers - 1934 -, 1934-1935 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Correspondence arranging conference on occupational status and to ensure employment opportunities for Black workers in Chicago; WPA projects correspondence with Howard D. Gould of the Chicago Urban League relating to a specific project - the Black Occupational Survey.
  - Illinois - Complaints -, 1934-1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing by the WPA
  - Illinois - General Correspondence -, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Black job applicants request aid in securing employment with the Illinois State Employment Service. Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing at the service.
  - Illinois - Proposed WPA Studies -, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Proposals for three WPA studies in Cook County, Illinois, re Black employment, occupations and population dynamics. Projects to be sponsored by the Illinois State Employment Service and conducted at the University of Chicago.
  - Illinois - Chicago - South Parkway Employment Office -, 1936-1939 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Black job applicants request aid in securing employment at the Illinois State Employment Service. Complaints from the service on a labor shortage of staff and racial segregation of offices.
  - Illinois - Chicago - West Wacker Drive Office -, 1936-1938 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Conference re Black employment. Report on meeting with the Chicago Urban League concerning the progress of Black employment in the WPA which resulted in the proposal to lobby government officials to demand the inclusion of Black employees on projects. Advertising for the re-election of Black Congressman Arthur Mitchell of Chicago.
  - Illinois - Survey -, 1936-1937 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Report on the relationship between the Illinois State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients occupations, local industry, job applicants and employee placements in Chicago, Cook County, and Illinois. Questionnaire concerning employment opportunities in retail trade for Blacks. Report on progress of Black employment in East Saint Louis, Chicago. Complaint from South Parkway office concerning racial segregation.
  - Indiana - Complaints -, 1936-1939 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks by the Indiana State Employment Service in the service's staffing. Alleged discrimination against Blacks resulting in under unemployment and unemployment.
  - Indiana - General Correspondence -, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Black job applicant requests aid in securing a position with the Indiana State Employment Service.
  - Indiana - Survey -, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Report on the relationship between the Indiana State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations and job applicants and employee placements from the service for Indianapolis and Indiana. Reports and statistics on the employment of Blacks in various Indiana Federal Emergency Relief Administration Housing projects. List of Black officials in the National Youth Administration.
  - Kansas - Complaints -, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Excerpts from a PWA Inspection Report alleging discriminations against Blacks by government officials and labor unions.
  - Kansas- Survey -, 1936-1937 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Racial Statistics on the occupational groups of job applicants and employee placements from the Kansas State Employment Service.
  - Kentucky - Complaints -, 1937-1939 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    alleged discrimination against Blacks. Report of wage differentials for Black and white employees of the Kentucky State Employment Service. Complaints by Blacks concerning living conditions, unemployment and poverty.
  - Kentucky - General Correspondence -, 1937-1940 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Correspondence arranging conference with the Kentucky State Employment Service. Black job applicants request aid in securing employment. Alleged dismissal of Black employee in the service because of local political affiliation.
  - Kentucky - Survey -, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    Racial statistics on population (1910-1933), emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry, and job applicants and employee placements from the Kentucky State employment Service for Louisville and Kentucky. Correspondence arranging conferences with the service concerning Black employment. Reports of field trips to Louisville, Kentucky.
  - Louisiana - Complaints -, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks by the Louisiana State Employment Service. Alleged discrimination against Blacks resulting in unemployment and poverty.
  - Louisiana - General Correspondence -, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Correspondence arranging conference with the Louisiana State Employment Service concerning Black employment. Discrimination against a potential Black employee of the Service.
  - Louisiana - Survey -, 1936-1938 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    Report on the relationship between the Louisiana State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Racial statistics on population (1910-33) emergency relief recipients, occupation, local industry and job applicants and employee placements from the Service, for New Orleans and Louisiana. Report on a field trip to Louisiana.
  - Maryland - Complaints -, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    alleged discrimination against Blacks in private sector industry and emergency relief projects in Maryland.
  - Maryland - General Correspondence -, 1936-1939 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    Correspondence arranging conference with Maryland State Employment Service concerning Black employment, Black job applicants request aid in securing a position with the Division of Negro Labor.
  - Maryland - Survey -, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Report on the relationship between the Maryland State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Statistics on population, occupations, wages, unemployment, and job applicants and employee placement from the service, divided by race. Report from the service on Black employment.
  - Massachusetts - General Correspondence -, 1937-1939 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    Petition from National Association for the Advancement of Colored People that public service corporations be prohibited from discrimination in employment on account of race. Report on conference with Massachusetts State Employment Service about Black employment.
  - Massachusetts - Survey -, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Racial statistics on population, occupations, unemployment and job applicants and employee placements from the Massachusetts State Employment Service. Meeting minutes from the service on Black employment.
- U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service State Files. (Box 17)
  - Michigan - Complaints -, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Alleged discrimination against a Black man by Michigan State Employment Service. Complaints of unemployment and poverty.
  - Michigan - Conference on Employment Problems of the Blacks - Detroit, 1940 - (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Papers include statistics on Black population, occupations, unemployment, vocational education, public welfare, WPA employees. Papers report on intellectual competence, family relationships, crime and delinquency, health and housing.
  - Michigan - Detroit -, 1937-1940 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Text from radio program about employment of Blacks by Michigan State Employment Service. Report on conference with service relating to Black employment.
  - Michigan - General Correspondence -, 1937-1940 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Correspondence arranging conference with Michigan State Employment Service. Blacks request information and aid in securing employment. Statistics on population divided by race for Flint, Grand Rapids, Detroit, and Michigan. Report on Black staffing problem.
  - Michigan - Survey -, 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Facts regarding PWA housing projects in Detroit. Report on the relationship between the Michigan State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry, unemployment and job applicants and employee placements for Detroit, Flint, Lansing, Grand Rapids, and Michigan. Conference report concerning Black employment.
  - Mississippi - General correspondence -, 1937-1938 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with Mississippi State Employment Service. Racial statistics on emergency relief recipients, occupations and job applicants, and employee placements from the service, in Meridan, Jackson, and Mississippi.
  - Mississippi - Survey -, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients and job applicants and employee placements from the Mississippi State Employment Service divided by race in Jackson, Meridan, and Mississippi.
  - Missouri - Complaints -, 1934-1938 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing by the Missouri State Employment Service.
  - Missouri - General Correspondence -, 1936-1940 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Correspondence concerning alleged discrimination against Blacks by the Missouri State Employment Service. Letters from Missouri Congressman, John J. Cochran, expressing dissatisfaction in Lawrence Oxley's speeches which contend that discrimination exists in many facets of the Federal government. Statistics on job applicants and employee placements, divided by race, from the service.
  - Missouri - Survey -, 1936-1938 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Report on the relationship between the Missouri State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Statistics include population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry, job applicants and employee placements from the service divided by race for Saint Louis, Kansas City, and Missouri. Conference report concerning the service and Black employment.
  - Nebraska - Survey -, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, and occupations divided by race in Omaha and Nebraska.
  - New Jersey - Complaints -, 1934-1939 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Black job applicants request aid in securing employment. Charges that Black migrants are depressing the farmhand wages and of alleged discrimination against Blacks in the shipbuilding industry in New Jersey.
  - New Jersey - General Correspondence -, 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Correspondence arranging conferences with New Jersey State Employment Service concerning Black employment. Letters from Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment.
  - New Jersey - Survey -, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations and unemployment divided by race in Jersey City, Newark, Camden, and New Jersey.
  - New York - Complaints -, 1934-1940 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks including barriers to entry into PWA employment where a closed shop agreement existed and labor unions bar Blacks from membership. Political cartoons and comments depicting discrimination against Blacks. Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment.
  - New York City - Housing Authority - Harlem Family Income Survey -, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Survey containing statistics on sources of income, percentage of income for rent, population density, composition of the family by race.
  - New York State - Commercial and Professional Division - Josephine P. Holmes -, 1936-1938 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Correspondence arranging conference with the New York State Employment Service concerning Black employees.
  - New York State - Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance - Fritz Kaufman -, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Proposal for study of the relationship of the New York State Employment Service with Blacks.
  - New York State - Harlem -, 1934-1940 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Annual reports from the Men's Industrial Service, Youth Statistics Divisions of the New York State Employment Service office in Harlem. Includes statistics on job applicants and placements.
  - New York State -New York World's Fair -, 1936-1939 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    United States Employment Service endeavors to secure employment for Blacks on the New York World's Fair projects. Requests by Black job applicants for aid in securing employment at the fair. Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing at the fair. Leaflet on the condition of the urban Black population.
  - New York State - William H. Lange -, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Routine correspondence
  - New York State - William H. Wilkinson -, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Statistics concerning job applicants and employee placements of the New York State Employment Service and the National Re-Employment Service.
  - New York State - Survey -, 1937-1938 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    Report on the relationship between the New York State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry, and job applicants and employee placements from the service, divided by race for New York City, Buffalo, and New York.
- U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service State Files. (Box 18)
  - North Carolina - Complaints -, 1935-1938 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Alleged discrimination against Blacks by North Carolina State Employment Service and private sector employers.
  - North Carolina - Examination information -, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Routine correspondence.
  - North Carolina - General Correspondence -, 1934-1940 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment. Pamphlet on North Carolina Committee on Black Affairs and a conference program for Black social workers.
  - North Carolina - Joseph R. Watts -, 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Alleged discrimination against Black employee in the North Carolina State Employment Services.
  - North Carolina - Survey -, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Report on the relationship between the North Carolina State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry, WPA staffing and job applicants, and employee placements of the service divided by race in Asheville, Charlotte, Greensboro, Winston-Salem Durham, Raleigh and North Carolina. Report on field trip to the service.
  - Ohio - Complaints -, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Alleged discrimination against Black job applicants by the Ohio State Employment Service.
  - Ohio - The Population of Hamilton County -, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Detailed report and statistics on population, race, characteristics, age, sex, employment, unemployment, marital status, religious affiliation, births, and deaths in Hamilton County.
  - Ohio - Columbus -, 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Correspondence arranging conference on Black employment with the Ohio State Employment Service, Columbus, office. Report on conference.
  - Ohio - General Correspondence -, 1936-1939 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment, with the Ohio State Employment Service. Letters from Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment. Newspaper article alleging discrimination against Blacks.
  - Ohio - Special Reports -, 1939-1940 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Procedures for referring Black job applicants. Report on Black employment from the Ohio State Employment Service and the Columbus Urban League. Survey of Black employee placement activities. Statistics on population, divided by race in Akron, Canton, Cincinnati, Cleveland, Columbus, Dayton, Toledo, Youngstown, and Ohio.
  - Ohio - Survey -, 1935-1937 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Statistics divided by race, on population, emergency relief recipients, and job applicants and employee placement from the Ohio State Employment Service and the National Re-employment Service for Cleveland, Columbus, Cincinnati, Akron, Youngstown, and Ohio.
  - Ohio - Cincinnati - Survey -, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Report on conference concerning Black job applicants and employee placements with the Ohio State Employment Service, Cincinnati Office.
  - Ohio - Cleveland Survey -, 1936-1937 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Report on the relationship between the Ohio State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry, and data on job applicants and employee placements from the service divided by race for Cleveland. Report concerning conference on Black employment with the service.
  - Oklahoma - General Correspondence -, 1937-1938 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Correspondence arranging conference with Oklahoma State Employment Service.
  - Oklahoma - Survey -, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry and on job applicants and employee placements from the Oklahoma State Employment Service divided by race for Oklahoma City, Tulsa, and Oklahoma. Report on field trip to the service.
  - Pennsylvania - Complaints -, 1936-1939 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Alleged discrimination against Black job applicants by the Pennsylvania State Employment Service. Alleged discrimination against Blacks resulting in unemployment and poverty.
  - Pennsylvania - General Correspondence -, 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with the Pennsylvania State Employment Service.
  - Pennsylvania - Harrisburg - Tensard DeWolf -, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania - Pittsburgh - George W. Dorsey -, 1934-1939 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with the Pennsylvania State Employment Service. Radio broadcast concerning Black employment by the service.
  - Pennsylvania - Survey -, 1936-1939 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    Conference report of the Pennsylvania State Employment Service concerning Black employment. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, and unemployment. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations and unemployment.
- U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service State Files. (Box 19)
  - Rhode Island -, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Fourth Annual Report of the Rhode Island Unemployment Compensation Board to the Governor for transmission to the General Assembly.
  - South Carolina - General Correspondence -, 1936-1939 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with the south Carolina State Employment Service.
  - South Carolina - Survey -, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, job applicants, and employee placements divided by race in Charleston, Columbia, Greenville, Spartanburg, and South Carolina.
  - Tennessee - General Correspondence -, 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Alleged discrimination against Black person complaining of violence, unemployment, and poverty.